{
    "courseTitle": "Research Methodology",
    "courseContent": {
        "1": [
            {
                "id": 1,
                "unit": 1,
                "title": "Webinar Speech: আমি কি পারব গবেষক হতে? - Can I become a researcher? - Mymensingh Eng. College",
                "src": "https://youtu.be/Ra6vA6-GbiI",
                "type": "lecture"
            },
            {
                "id": 2,
                "unit": 1,
                "title": "লেকচার ১ঃ গবেষণা কি? কেন করব? লাভ কি? । What is research? Why to conduct research?",
                "src": "https://youtu.be/J9j7tGNzA3o",
                "type": "lecture"
            },
            {    
                "id": 3,
                "unit": 1,
                "title": "Quiz",
                "type":"quiz",
                "quiz":[
                    {
                        "question":"Which one is true when someone has average talent?",
                        "option":["He can not do good research","He should give more efforts","He must find a way to improve his talent","None of the above"],
                        "answer":["2"]
                    },
                    {
                        "question":"Which option(s) is/are true for research?",
                        "option":["It is a well planned process","It focuses on a wide scope","Following a structure is not essential","Some steps must be performed in an order"],
                        "answer":["1","4"]
                    },
                    {
                        "question":"Which option(s) is/are true for a research question?",
                        "option":["It is not always necessary","It helps to focus on research","Finding the answer of the research question is mandatoryl","If the answer of the research question is 'no', then it is not an answer"],
                        "answer":["2","3"]
                    },
                    {
                        "question":"Which of the following could be the research?",
                        "option":["Separating truths from lies","Reproduce an existing method","Prove a supposition","Investigating reasons behind a particular problem"],
                        "answer":["1","3","4"]
                    },
                    {
                        "question":"What are the opportunities for a good researcher",
                        "option":["Not much options are available","Teaching position","Work as a researcher in an industry","None of the above"],
                        "answer":["1","2"]
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "id": 4,
                "unit": 1,
                "title": " লেকচার ২.১ঃ গবেষণার প্রকারভেদ উদাহরণসহ (বেসিক ও এপ্লাইড রিসার্চ)। Types of research",
                "src": "https://youtu.be/nDSTyWhe2Aw",
                "type": "lecture"
            },
            {
                "id": 5,
                "unit": 1,
                "title": "লেকচার ২.২ঃ গবেষণার প্রকারভেদ ও পার্থক্য (কোয়ালিটেটিভ ও কোয়ান্টিটেটিভ)। Types of research",
                "src": "https://youtu.be/dMCHKKuBm8M",
                "type": "lecture"
            },
            {    
                "id": 6,
                "unit": 1,
                "title": "Quiz",
                "type":"quiz",
                "quiz":[
                    {
                        "question":"How many types applied research usually have?",
                        "option":["2","3","4","5"],
                        "answer":["2"]
                    },
                    {
                        "question":"Theoretical research must lead to immediate applications.",
                        "option":["True","False"],
                        "answer":["2"]
                    },
                    {
                        "question":"Mark the basic research examples from the following list.",
                        "option":["Einstein's Theory of Relativity","Is current technology used for children helpful or harmful?","How did the universe begin?","A study of factors impacting each stage of product life cycle"],
                        "answer":["1","3","4"]
                    },
                    {
                        "question":"What are characteristics of quantitative research?",
                        "option":["It has conclusion","It is descriptive and uses words","Results are presents using graphs","Research question involves ‘why’"],
                        "answer":["1","3"]
                    },
                    {
                        "question":"Statistical analysis is used to report data in qualitative research.",
                        "option":["True","False"],
                        "answer":["2"]
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "id": 7,
                "unit": 1,
                "title": "লেকচার ৩.১ঃ গবেষণার টপিক সিলেকশন । Research Topic Selection",
                "src": "https://youtu.be/ulmt9Ck0UAA",
                "type": "lecture"
            },
            {
                "id": 8,
                "unit": 1,
                "title": "লেকচার ৩.২ঃ বিষয় ভিত্তিক গবেষণাপত্র ফ্রি ডাউনলোড । Download Topic Related Articles Free",
                "src": "https://youtu.be/BzG2O1h80Ys",
                "type": "lecture"
            },
            {
                "id": 9,
                "unit": 1,
                "title": "Assignment 1",
                "description": "Final Paper Assignment Description. Paper Goals: This final paper is the capstone assignment of COM 431 since it requires you to use all that you have learned ...",
                "type": "assignment"
            }
        ],
        "2": [
            {
                "id": 10,
                "unit": 2,
                "title": "লেকচার ৩.৩ঃ কিভাবে গবেষণাপত্র পড়ব? । How to read research paper?",
                "src": "https://youtu.be/3FJ0RTBw4tM",
                "type": "lecture"
            },
            {    
                "id": 11,
                "unit": 2,
                "title": "Quiz",
                "type":"quiz",
                "quiz":[
                    {
                        "question":"It is not necessary to track relevant files in the primary stage of a research.",
                        "option":["True","False"],
                        "answer":["2"]
                    },
                    {
                        "question":"What are the main features of the topic selection process?",
                        "option":["Materials are available","Topic could be unoriginal","Literatures are incomprehensible","Problem is solvable"],
                        "answer":["1","4"]
                    },
                    {
                        "question":"Google scholar is more helpful than google for searching a research article.",
                        "option":["True","False"],
                        "answer":["1"]
                    },
                    {
                        "question":"What are the advantages of Mendeley?",
                        "option":["It is free","It generates references","It automatically marks important lines in a research article","It facilitates collaboration with others"],
                        "answer":["1","2","4"]
                    },
                    {
                        "question":"S. Kesav suggested a method to read a paper. What is the method?",
                        "option":["Thoroughly reading method","Briefly Study method","2 Pass method","3 Pass method"],
                        "answer":["3"]
                    },
                    {
                        "question":"S. Kesav suggested a method to read a paper. What is the method?",
                        "option":["Read only the abstract","Focus on graphs, tables","Mark unread papers in the reference section","Pay attention to details"],
                        "answer":["2","3"]      
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "id": 12,
                "unit": 2,
                "title": "লেকচার ৪.১ঃ ভালো গবেষণাপত্র/জার্নাল খুঁজে পাওয়ার উপায় । How to find out good quality papers/journals",
                "src": "https://youtu.be/QAUfuu_1Hhs",
                "type": "lecture"
            },
            {
                "id": 13,
                "unit": 2,
                "title": "লেকচার ৪.২ঃ ভুয়া জার্নাল/পাবলিশার চেনার উপায় । How to avoid fake/predatory journals/publishers?",
                "src": "https://youtu.be/XRgpEPnZwPM",
                "type": "lecture"
            },
            {
                "id": 14,
                "unit": 2,
                "title": "লেকচার ৪.৩ঃ লিটারেচার রিভিউ লেখার নিয়ম উদাহরণসহ । How to write literature review with examples?",
                "src": "https://youtu.be/KL8AghDVA_Y",
                "type": "lecture"
            },
            {    
                "id": 15,
                "unit": 2,
                "title": "Quiz",
                "type":"quiz",
                "quiz":[
                    {
                        "question":"Which one is the key reason to conduct literature review?",
                        "option":["To be familiar with existing systems","To develop knowledge in that field","To find research gap","To write the literature review in your article"],
                        "answer":["3"]
                    },
                    {
                        "question":"Publishing more papers in predatory journals is better than less papers in qualitiful jornal.",
                        "option":["True","False"],
                        "answer":["2"]
                    },
                    {
                        "question":"Which of the following are the characteristics of predatory journals?",
                        "option":["Send spam emails","Receive government fund","Indexed by SCI","Claims about metrics are false"],
                        "answer":["1","4"]
                    },
                    {
                        "question":"Literature Review can be written Chronologically or Thematically.",
                        "option":["True","False"],
                        "answer":["1"]
                    },
                    {
                        "question":"Which section of the literature review should include errors of the paper, according to Thompson Rivers University?",
                        "option":["Introduction","Main Body","Conclusion","Reference"],
                        "answer":["2"]
                    },
                    {
                        "question":"Why should different verbs be used while writing literature review?",
                        "option":["They improve writing quality","Otherwise readers might get bored","They increase the chance of acceptance","None of the above"],
                        "answer":["1","2"]      
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "id": 16,
                "unit": 2,
                "title": "লেকচার ৫.১ঃ রিসার্চ/লিটারেচার গ্যাপ বের করার উপায় । How to find out research/literature gaps?",
                "src": "https://youtu.be/Mcz64BZEuv0",
                "type": "lecture"
            },
            {
                "id": 17,
                "unit": 2,
                "title": "লেকচার ৫.২ঃ রিসার্চ কোয়েশ্চেন নির্ধারণ । Determination of research questions",
                "src": "https://youtu.be/e6-4kFmOVAk",
                "type": "lecture"
            },
            {
                "id": 18,
                "unit": 2,
                "title": "লেকচার ৫.৩ঃ রিসার্চ হাইপোথেসিস সেট করা । Setting Research Hypothesis",
                "src": "https://youtu.be/J6UXlT8IN6Y",
                "type": "lecture"
            },
            {    
                "id": 19,
                "unit": 2,
                "title": "Quiz",
                "type":"quiz",
                "quiz":[
                    {
                        "question":"One should select a research topic that motivates him.",
                        "option":["True","False"],
                        "answer":["1"]
                    },
                    {
                        "question":"Logical operators are useful in the articles searching process.",
                        "option":["True","False"],
                        "answer":["1"]
                    },
                    {
                        "question":"What are the features of a good research question?",
                        "option":["Focused on a particular problem","It must be easy enough to be answered by anyone","It has a wide scope","Feasible to achieve goals within an estimated period"],
                        "answer":["1","4"]
                    },
                    {
                        "question":"'Unfair relationships may result in bad consequences in life.' - in this sentence, which one is a dependent variable?",
                        "option":["Unfair relationship","Bad consequences","Result","None of them"],
                        "answer":["2"]
                    },
                    {
                        "question":"‘ People over 50s are at greater risk of getting infected by the Covid-19’. If this is the alternative hypothesis, which one is the null hypothesis?",
                        "option":["‘ People over 50s are at lower risk of getting infected by the Covid-19’","‘ Age of people has no relation with the Covid-19 infection’","‘ People over 50s are at no risk of getting infected by the Covid-19’","None of the above"],
                        "answer":["2"]
                    }
                ]
            }
        ],
        "3": [
            {
                "id": 20,
                "unit": 3,
                "title": "লেকচার ৬.১ঃ বিভিন্ন ধরণের রিসার্চ আর্টিকেল । Different types of research articles",
                "src": "https://youtu.be/Qrz00d_JFiY",
                "type": "lecture"
            },
            {
                "id": 21,
                "unit": 3,
                "title": "লেকচার ৬.২ঃ রিসার্চ আর্টিকেল/প্রোপোজাল-এর সাধারণ গঠণ । Structure of Research Article/Proposal",
                "src": "https://youtu.be/65N34eV6GFo",
                "type": "lecture"
            },
            {    
                "id": 22,
                "unit": 3,
                "title": "Quiz",
                "type":"quiz",
                "quiz":[
                    {
                        "question":"Which one is the commentary article?",
                        "option":["Describing a method to detect Covid-19","Summarizing 100 research articles","Providing an opinion about a newly invented technique","Explain something through text and visual"],
                        "answer":["3"]
                    },
                    {
                        "question":"The title of paper should be __.",
                        "option":["Concise","Contain jargons","Reflect contents of the paper","Attractive"],
                        "answer":["1","3","4"]
                    },
                    {
                        "question":"Why are keywords so important?",
                        "option":["They facilitates searching process","They increase the chance of acceptance","They are essential for indexing","None of the above"],
                        "answer":["1","3"]
                    },
                    {
                        "question":"Which one the introduction section should not contain?",
                        "option":["Relevant works","Problems associated with existing solutions","Some portions from result, discussion, and conclusion","Major scientific contributions on which your work is based"],
                        "answer":["3"]
                    },
                    {
                        "question":"Which section should include the purpose of the work?",
                        "option":["Abstract","Results","Introduction","Conclusion"],
                        "answer":["3"]
                    },
                    {
                        "question":"Which sections is not included in the research proposal?",
                        "option":["Introduction","Methods","Results","Reference"],
                        "answer":["3"]
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "id": 23,
                "unit": 3,
                "title": "লেকচার ৭.১ঃ রিসার্চ মেথডোলজি-এর বেসিক ধারণা । Research Methodology Basics",
                "src": "https://youtu.be/UcDMFlnYHmA",
                "type": "lecture"
            },
            {
                "id": 24,
                "unit": 3,
                "title": "লেকচার ৭.২.১ঃ রিসার্চ মেথডোলজি লিখার ধাপসমূহ (১ম অংশ) । Steps in writing research methodology",
                "src": "https://youtu.be/2As0JbLEWpI",
                "type": "lecture"
            },
            {
                "id": 25,
                "unit": 3,
                "title": "লেকচার ৭.২.২ঃ রিসার্চ মেথডোলজি লিখার ধাপসমূহ (২য় অংশ) । Steps in writing research methodology",
                "src": "https://youtu.be/90eLJ68SLus",
                "type": "lecture"
            },
            {    
                "id": 26,
                "unit": 3,
                "title": "Quiz",
                "type":"quiz",
                "quiz":[
                    {
                        "question":"Research Methodology and Methods are different things.",
                        "option":["True","False"],
                        "answer":["1"]
                    },
                    {
                        "question":"Procedure is a sequence of ___.",
                        "option":["Methods","Techniques","Approaches","Methodology"],
                        "answer":["2"]
                    },
                    {
                        "question":"Which section is not included in methodology?",
                        "option":["The way of analysing data","Reasons for choosing a particular method","The interpretation of obtained results","Tools used to select data"],
                        "answer":["3"]
                    },
                    {
                        "question":"Ethical information is not necessary to include in methodology.",
                        "option":["True","False"],
                        "answer":["2"]
                    },
                    {
                        "question":"Interview is a qualitative data collection method.",
                        "option":["True","False"],
                        "answer":["1"]
                    },
                    {
                        "question":"During data collection through survey, which of the following need(s) to mention?",
                        "option":["Time period of survey","Audience selection method","The design of experiment","Percentage of participant response"],
                        "answer":["1","2","4"]
                    },
                    {
                        "question":"When the range of a specific variable is 10-20, which of the following is the outlier?",
                        "option":["10","15","30","None of the above"],
                        "answer":["3"]
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "id": 27,
                "unit": 3,
                "title": "লেকচার ৮.১ঃ ডাটা কালেকশন মেথডসমূহ ও স্যাম্পলিং । Data Collection Methods and Sampling",
                "src": "https://youtu.be/DhQlqnbs1SY",
                "type": "lecture"
            },
            {
                "id": 28,
                "unit": 3,
                "title": "লেকচার ৮.২ঃ লাইকার্ট স্কেল - এর মাধ্যমে ডাটা কালেকশন ও এনালাইসিস । Likert Scale - Data Collection",
                "src": "https://youtu.be/AaPzouNyjlo",
                "type": "lecture"
            },
            {    
                "id": 29,
                "unit": 3,
                "title": "Quiz",
                "type":"quiz",
                "quiz":[
                    {
                        "question":"Email is a type of survey based on ___.",
                        "option":["Data collection method","Time","Industry","None of the above"],
                        "answer":["1"]
                    },
                    {
                        "question":"Gathering information from witnesses of an event is a ___ survey.",
                        "option":["Longitudinal","Online","Retrospective","Cross-sectional"],
                        "answer":["3"]
                    },
                    {
                        "question":"Sample selection based on criteria is entailed in probability sampling.",
                        "option":["True","False"],
                        "answer":["2"]
                    },
                    {
                        "question":"Lower margin of error means higher proximity to exact answers at a given confidence level.",
                        "option":["True","False"],
                        "answer":["1"]
                    },
                    {
                        "question":"Likert Chart is an important option to collect ___ type date.",
                        "option":["Qualitative","Quantitative","Both","None of the above"],
                        "answer":["2"]
                    },
                    {
                        "question":"Assigning a number to each type in Likert data is the best way to analyze.",
                        "option":["True","False"],
                        "answer":["2"]
                    }
                ]
            }
        ],
        "4": [
            {
                "id": 30,
                "unit": 4,
                "title": "লেকচার ৯ঃ রেজাল্ট প্রদর্শণের বিভিন্ন পদ্ধতি ও টুলস, ইভালুয়েশন । Result Representation and Evaluation",
                "src": "https://youtu.be/RVLByrdYE0o",
                "type": "lecture"
            },
            {    
                "id": 31,
                "unit": 4,
                "title": "Quiz",
                "type":"quiz",
                "quiz":[
                    {
                        "question":"A graph or chart or diagram is a diagrammatic illustration of a set of data.",
                        "option":["True","False"],
                        "answer":["1"]
                    },
                    {
                        "question":"A pie chart is a chart that presents categorical data with rectangular bars.",
                        "option":["True","False"],
                        "answer":["2"]
                    },
                    {
                        "question":"Bars in a bar chart can be plotted horizontally or vertically.",
                        "option":["True","False"],
                        "answer":["1"]
                    },
                    {
                        "question":"Origin is the data analysis and  graphing software of choice for over half a million scientists.",
                        "option":["True","False"],
                        "answer":["1"]
                    },
                    {
                        "question":"Theoretical proof is a data evaluation technique.",
                        "option":["True","False"],
                        "answer":["1"]
                    }
                ]
            },
            {
                "id": 32,
                "unit": 4,
                "title": "লেকচার ১০.১ঃ রেফারেন্সিং ও সাইটেশন স্টাইল । Referencing and Citation Styles",
                "src": "https://youtu.be/-LaO5mNdgdY",
                "type": "lecture"
            },
            {
                 "id": 33,
                 "unit": 4,
                 "title": "লেকচার ১০.২ঃ রেফারেন্সিং টুলস (Mendeley, EndNote, Zotero) - এর ব্যবহার । Usage of Referencing Tools",
                 "src": "https://youtu.be/4F1SFzGAG0M",
                 "type": "lecture"
            },
            {    
                "id": 34,
                "unit": 4,
                "title": "Quiz",
                "type":"quiz",
                "quiz":[
                    {
                        "question":"Which one is a referencing tool ?",
                        "option":["Matlab","Origin","R","Mendeley"],
                        "answer":["4"]
                    },
                    {
                        "question":"Generally the references are underlined.",
                        "option":["True","False"],
                        "answer":["2"]
                    },
                    {
                        "question":"What is MLA?",
                        "option":["Data evaluation technique","Data visualization tool","Citation format","Data referencing tool"],
                        "answer":["3"]
                    },
                    {
                        "question":"What is included in Apa citation ?",
                        "option":["Author’s name","The year of publication","Page number","Volume number"],
                        "answer":["1","2","3"]
                    },
                    {
                        "question":"Referencing is used to tell the reader where ideas are from.",
                        "option":["True","False"],
                        "answer":["1"]
                    }
                ]
            }

        ],
        "5" : [
            {
                "id": 35,
                "unit": 5,
                "title": "লেকচার ১১.১ঃ রিসার্চ ইথিক্স । Research Ethics",
                "src": "https://youtu.be/Xl7TFPLGNuI",
                "type": "lecture"
            },
            {
                "id": 36,
                "unit": 5,
                "title": "লেকচার ১১.২ঃ প্ল্যাজারিজম (রচনাচুরি) ও তা এড়িয়ে চলার উপায় । Plagiarism and How to Avoid it",
                "src": "https://youtu.be/KeBORaCAtEI",
                "type": "lecture"
            },
            {
                "id": 37,
                "unit": 5,
                "title": "লেকচার ১১.৩ঃ প্ল্যাজারিজম নির্ণায়ক (Turnitin, Grammarly) ও প্যারাফ্রেজিং (Quillbot) টুলসের ব্যবহার।",
                "src": "https://youtu.be/XSudeNYJQo0",
                "type": "lecture"
            },
            {    
                "id": 38,
                "unit": 5,
                "title": "Quiz",
                "type":"quiz",
                "quiz":[
                    {
                        "question":"Research ethics provides guidelines for the responsible conduct of research.",
                        "option":["True","False"],
                        "answer":["1"]
                    },
                    {
                        "question":"Research approval is necessary to protect the rights of the researchers to carry out a lawful research.",
                        "option":["True","False"],
                        "answer":["1"]
                    },
                    {
                        "question":"What is fabrication?",
                        "option":["Manipulating research materials","Appropriations of another person’s idea","Making up data or results","None of the above"],
                        "answer":["3"]
                    },
                    {
                        "question":"What is paraphrasing?",
                        "option":["Directly copying a passage of text without citation","Combining text and ideas from different sources without citation","Rephrasing someone else's ideas without citation","None of the above"],
                        "answer":["3"]
                    },
                    {
                        "question":"Which one is a paraphrasing tool?",
                        "option":["Grammarly","Turnitin","Quillbot","Ithenticate"],
                        "answer":["3"]
                    },
                    {
                        "question":"Google can be used as a plagiarism detection tool.",
                        "option":["True","False"],
                        "answer":["1"]
                    }
        
                ]
            },
           {
            "id": 39,
            "unit": 5,
            "title": "লেকচার ১২.১ঃ পেপার সাবমিশন চেকলিস্ট, পিয়ার রিভিউ পদ্ধতি এবং জার্ণাল ফাইন্ডার ও সিলেকশন।",
            "src": "https://youtu.be/HLddqSPFVAQ",
            "type": "lecture"
           },
           {
            "id": 40,
            "unit": 5,
            "title": "লেকচার ১২.২ঃ পেপার সাবমিশনে ভূল, কাভার/রিভিউ রেসপন্স লেটার,পেপার রিজেক্ট হলে করণীয়।",
            "src": "https://youtu.be/Lh6Lah-AJMI",
            "type": "lecture"
           },
           {
            "id": 41,
            "unit": 5,
            "title": "১২.৩ঃ Wiley জার্ণালে পেপার সাবমিশন । Paper submission to Wiley Journal",
            "src": "https://youtu.be/3N3qWiBsIwM",
            "type": "lecture"
            },
            {    
                "id": 42,
                "unit": 5,
                "title": "Quiz",
                "type":"quiz",
                "quiz":[
                    {
                        "question":"What is/are the reasons for early rejection?",
                        "option":["Paper is a routine application of well-known methods","Paper presents an incremental or is limited in scope","Novelty or significance are not immediately evident","None of the above"],
                        "answer":["1","2","3"]
                    },
                    {
                        "question":"What does ‘Revise & resubmit’ mean?",
                        "option":["The journal will not publish the paper","The journal will publish the paper & ask the author to make small changes","The journal is willing to reconsider the paper in another round of decision making  after the authors make major changes","None of the above"],
                        "answer":["3"]
                    },
                    {
                        "question":"Nearly every manuscript needs revision.",
                        "option":["True","False"],
                        "answer":["1"]
                    },
                    {
                        "question":"Minor revision guarantees acceptance.",
                        "option":["True","False"],
                        "answer":["2"]
                    },
                    {
                        "question":"What is ‘Wiley?",
                        "option":["A referencing tool","A journal","citation format","None of the above"],
                        "answer":["2"]
                    }
        
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    "totalItem": 42
}